Name: ABHIJEET RANE

E-mail: abhijeet.rane@gmail.com **Mobile**: +91-9967840909

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

 Accomplished Java Full Stack Developer with total 21 years of global experience in designing and developing complex enterprise cloud based and on premises applications in Java, Springboot framework , Spring framework , Struts 2 framework , Javascript , Angular , PL/SQL and AWS cloud.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Programming Languages	Java , PL /SQL		
Web services	Restful web services		
Frameworks	Spring Boot, Spring Security, Spring Data JPA , Springframework, Struts 2 framework		
ORM Framework	Hibernate		
Cloud Computing	Amazon Cloud Services(AWS) EC2, S3 , ECS , Fargate ,RDS, API Gateway , Lambda		
Container technologies	Docker		
CI/CD technologies	Jenkins , AWS Code build , AWS Code Deploy		
Unit testing	Junit , Mockito		
Front End Technologies	Reactjs , Angular, Javascript , HTML , CSS , JSP		
Build Tools	Gradle, Maven, Ant		
RDBMS Technologies	Oracle, SQL Server, MySQL		
Web servers	Apache Tomcat Server, Apache HTTP Server		
Application servers	Wildfly(JBOSS), Weblogic, IBM Websphere, Glassfish		
Messaging framework	RabbitMQ		
Legacy framework	EJB		
Version Control Tools	Git, SVN, CVS, Tortoise, Visual SourceSafe		
IDE	Intellij IDEA , STS , Eclipse , Netbeans		
Source Code Editor	Visual Studio Code , Eclipse Theia		
Reporting Tools	Crystal Reports, Oracle Reports, Apache POI, iText		
ETL Tools	Jasper ETL		
Operating Systems	Linux, Unix, MS Windows		

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Name of Company	Post	Duration
In Solutions Global Ltd	Manager	Jan 2024 - Present
Encora Innovation Labs	Technical Lead	Sept 2022 - Mar 2023
BNED Loudcloud	Technical Lead	Dec 2020 - Sept 2022
J.P.Morgan Chase	Associate	Sept 2018 - Oct 2020
Chenoa Private Ltd.	Lead Developer	July 2016 - July 2018
Intellect Design Arena Ltd	Team Leader	July 2015 - Mar 2016
Datamatics Global Services Ltd	Consultant	Jan 2012 - May 2015
Tata Consultancy Services Ltd	I.T Analyst	Oct 2010 - Jan 2012
Martha Stewart Living Omnimedia	Application Support Developer	May 2008 - Jul 2009
Indus Consultancy Services	Programming Analyst	Jun 2006 – Apr 2008
National Stock Exchange . IT	Trainee Associate System Analyst	Oct 2003 – Jul 2004

KEY PROJECTS UNDERTAKEN

1. Project Name: BBPS (Bharat Bill Payment System) Biller

The application is for integrating the BBPS switch/smart router with backend CCMS(Credit Card Management System).It is implemented in Java 21, Springboot, Microservices, Oracle (PL/SQL), Fedora Linux, Maven and STS IDE.

2. Project Name: Recurring Payments

The application is for setting up mandate for recurring payment for the customer. The money is deducted from customer's credit card or debit card at predefined fixed interval. We have integrated the AFA (Additional Factor of Authentication) with pre debit notification. It is implemented in Java 11, Springboot, Microservices, Oracle(PL/SQL), Angular/Javascript, HTML, CSS Fedora Linux, Mayen and STS IDE.

3. Project Name: Corporate Travel Booking IVR Software

The application is for booking tickets for customers of our client in America. The software is written as integrator between IVR (Interactive Voice Response) and backend process using Avaya Orchestration Designer. The customer calls to IVR phone number the Nuance biometric voice authentication system validates the customer and then allows the customer to proceed. It is implemented in Java 8 , Springboot, Microservices , Linux, MySQL , Gradle and Intellij IDEA IDE.

4. Project Name: Adoption and Insights for students and teachers of universities.

The application is for adoption of books for courses to be taught in the colleges and universities of America. The professor adopts the book for the course to teach before the semester starts and the books are delivered to the students before the first day of the term or semester. It is implemented in Java 8 ,Springboot , Microservices , MySQL , Maven , Junit 5 , Sonarqube , OWASP maven plugin, Intellij IDEA IDE, Alpine Linux ,AWS Cloud (ECS , EC2, Lambda ,S3 bucket, Fargate , Api Gateway and RDS) and CI/CD tool used is AWS Code build and Code pipeline.

5. Project Name: Derivatives - Chatbot

The client is internal to bank. It is a derivative chat bot product. The chatbot answers question of operation users for financial products like derivatives FX , Rates CDS. The core application logic is written in Java 8. It communicates with Oracle and Marklogic databases. The chatbot logic is written in expression language.

6. Project Name: Derivatives – Settlement and Affirmation

The client is internal to bank. It is a derivative product. The different products like Rates, FX, CDS are handled by the product. It manages settlement and confirmation of financial products. The application logic is written in Java 8. It communicates with Oracle and Marklogic databases using Spring framework. CI/CD tool used is Jenkins.

7. Project Name: Homecarevitals - Home Healthcare for Seniors

The client are hospitals which provide home healthcare facility. The software allows hospitals to track the patient vital parameters like Blood pressure, Fasting Blood Glucose, Weight etc. The patient enters the data in an Android application which is stored on server. The tele-health nurse receives alert based on vital parameters which cross the predefined upper and lower limit. The nurse takes action like calling physician, changing medication etc. It is implemented in Java 8 , Springboot , Microservices , MySQL , Maven , STS IDE , AWS Cloud (EC2 , RDS and S3 bucket)

EDUCATION

	College / School	University /	Year of	GPA /
Degree		Board	Passing	Percentage
Master of Science (M.S) in Computer Science	Marist College, Poughkeepsie, New York ,USA	Marist College, Poughkeepsie, New York ,USA	2006	3.739 / 4.0 CGPA
Bachelor of Engineering (B.E) in Information Technology	Vidyavardhini's College of Engineering and Technology, Vasai , Palghar District , Maharashtra, India	Mumbai University	2003	65.64 % - First Class
H.S.C (12 th Grade)	D.G.Ruparel College of Arts, Science and Commerce, Matunga ,Mumbai District, Maharashtra , India	Maharashtra State Board	1999	86.50 % - Distinction
S.S.C(10 th Grade)	St Xavier's High School , Nashik Road, Nashik District , Maharashtra , India	Maharashtra State Board	1997	81.33 % - Distinction

Awards

- Sir Ratan Tata & The JRD Tata Scholarships for Academic Excellence in year 2002.
- Datamatics Spot Award for Indepay Project in year 2015.